# Tagir Sharipov

+ 39-346-313-85-24 | semplice@giallo.it | linkedin.com/in/tagir-sharipov | github.com/TagirSharipov

#### SUMMARY

Experienced software engineer with over 15 years in the industry. Based in Italy and working remotely, I have successfully delivered complex projects for both major corporations and startups. My expertise includes business analysis, system architecture, and team leadership.

# EXPERIENCE

# Senior Frontend Developer

2022 - Present

Keybiz SRL

Italy, Rome, remote

- Developed a complex web app for the largest telecommunication operator with Tanstack Query/Form/Router and Typescript
- Integrated OpenAPI generators to create API calls, YAML data schemas and TypeScript interface definitions, which reduced backend and frontend integration efforts by 50%
- Created NPM packages of interactive data visualizations (choropleth maps, heatmaps, radar charts, chord diagram, network charts, etc.) with **React and D3.js**.
- Implemented CI/CD pipelines with GitHub Actions, Docker and Azure Devops
- Built microfrontends with NPM: packaged each microfrontend as an NPM package, allowing teams to develop, test, and deploy independently.
- Advocated for well-tested and documented, high quality code. Participated in the development of **code** guidelines.

Software Developer

2021 - 2022

Nexi Digital

Italy, Milano, remote contractor

• Delivered electronic payments management portal with complex async flows, custom **UI design system** and **PKCE** authentication flow utilizing **Redux-sagas**, **Axios**, **SASS** .

# Senior Fullstack Developer

2017 - 2021

Size4.me SRL

Italy, Massa

- Delivered a web service helping to choose the right size for online shoppers.
- Selected and implemented the technology stack (React, Typescript, Next, Redux, DynamoDB, Node)
- Built out the frontend and backend components including authentication (Authorization Code Flow + integration with FB and Google), RESTful API, material design, NoSQL db
- Maintained system performance with Linux, Raven, Amazon Web Services
- Developed **Webpack** configurations for various build modes( production/development/separate bundles/multiple entry points).
- The web service acquired 45k users in the first 3 months after launch.

#### Senior Software Developer

2013 - 2016

Polnakorzina

Moscow, Russia

• Developed the admin part and front-office of an affiliate management system using PHP, MySQL, jQuery

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frameworks: React, Next.js, Node.js, React-Native, Redux, Redux-Saga, Webpack, Vite, Tanstack Query/Router/Form, MSW, Axios, Zod, PrimeReact, Material-UI, SASS, Styled components, Tailwind

Languages: JavaScript, Typescript, HTML/CSS, PHP, SQL

Developer Tools: Git, Gitlab, Github, Docker, Amazon Web Services, Oracle, MySQL, Firebase, Dynamo DB,

Swagger, Postman, Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Jira

Libraries: D3.js

#### EDUCATION

## Ufa State Aviation Technical University

Ufa, Russia

Master in Computer Science (Software Engineering), Bachelor in Business Administration

diploma with honor

# LANGUAGES